

Contact



Thakur Complex Kandivali
East
400101 Mumbai, India

Skills

- JVM
- MySQL
- Scala
- Project Management JIRA
- Hibernate
- Core Java
- · Java 8
- Spring Framework
- · Java Development
- Leadership skills
- · JIRA Agile
- Team Leadership
- Java technology
- Project Management
- Solution Implementation
- Technical Architecture

Swastik Srivastava Senior Technical Consultant

About Me

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Java, C++, JavaScript, OOPS. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) focused in Information Technology and Master of Business Administration focused in Information Technology.

Date of birth: August 4, 1997 Place of birth: Unnao, India

Work experience

SENIOR TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

October 2023 - present

Ernst & Young

Client- Morgan Stanley

Determined areas for improvement and implemented processes to alleviate problems. "Analyzed problematic areas to provide recommendations and solutions. "Streamlined processes to cut downtime and optimize employee productivity. "Identified business issues through careful collaboration with key stakeholders. "Closely monitored and updated company systems for efficiency, output and other factors to improve overall productivity.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

July 2022 - October 2023

Diebold Nixdorf

Client- Sharjah Islamic Bank

Collaborated with project managers across Middle East onsite and remote both to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development. "Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases." Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs, and improving functionality. "Translated customer requirements into written use cases." Coordinated deployments of new software, feature updates.

SYSTEM ENGINEER

January 2020 - July 2022

TATA Consultancy Services

Client- TCSiON

Full Stack Development of Job posting platform for TCS iON. "Write production ready frontend and backend code." Responsible for Sonar code review, RCA and x Production issues. "Responsible for Unit, Integration testing and Fix QA,Performance, Security and UI defects. "Communicate with multiple teams for the requirements and deployment of the code within time frame. "Responsible for creating,optimizing and execute SQL Scripts on production and Non Prod Environments." Supervise the team members and inspect their code.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

June 2018 - August 2018

Speridian Technologies

Languages

Hindi - Native English - Advanced

Education

MASTER'S DEGREE

2019 - 2021

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University, Information Technoogy - Lucknow

BACHELOR'S DEGREE

2015 - 2019

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University, Information Technology - Lucknow

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/swastik-srivastava/

Certificates

Java Development , Java Advance , mySQL